Finding Aid for James J. Duderstadt Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Digital Documents
  - Faculty Archives, 1968-ongoing; 1312 digital files
    - Aligning American Higher Education with a 21st-Century Public Agenda (Final), 6/8/2008
    - Creating a National Network of Energy Discovery-Innovation Institutes: A Step Toward America's Energy Sustainability, 9/26/2008
    - Aligning American Higher Education with a Twenty-First Century Public Agenda, 2009
    - Blueprint for American Prosperity - Unleashing the Potential of a Metropolitan Nation, 2009
    - Changing University Missions and Profiling in the United States: Some Lessons Learned in the New World, 2009
    - The Changing nature of the American Research University Ecosystem, 2009
    - Engineering for a Changing Road, A Roadmap to the Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education, 2009
    - Engineering for a Changing Road, A Roadmap to the Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education, 2009
    - Engineering for a Changing World - The Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education (Canada), 2009
    - Engineering for a Changing World - The Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education (Grasso), 2009
    - Key Points of Brookings Institution Next Energy Project, 2009
    - NASULGC Presidents Address, 2009
    - New Research Paradigms for Technological Innovation, 2009
    - Possible Futures for the Research Library in the 21st Century, 2009
    - Possible Futures for the Research Library in the 21st Century (annotated), 2009
    - A Proposed Study of the Changing Nature of the American Research University Ecosystem, 2009
    - A Roadmap to Michigan's Future, 2009
    - Senate Assembly Address, 2009
    - Time to Get it Right: Staying Competitive in the New Economy - The View From Year Five, 2009
    - Universities and Innovation, 2009
    - The View from Year Five, 2009
    - Energy Discovery-Innovation Institutes: A Step Toward America's Energy Sustainability, 2009-02
    - Energy Discovery-Innovation Institutes: A Step Toward America's Energy Sustainability, 2009-02
    - Energy Discovery-Innovation Institutes: A Step toward America's Energy Sustainability, 2009-02
    - Energy Discovery-Innovation Institutes: A Step Toward Energy Sustainability, 2/9/2009
    - University of Georgia Address, 2/9/2009
    - Current Global Trends in Higher Education and Research: Their Impact on Europe, 3/12/2009
    - New University Paradigms for Technological Innovation, 5/15/2009
    - McGill Engineering Commencement Address - JJD, 5/25/2009
    - McGill Commencement Address, 5/26/2009
    - Dartmouth Engineering Investiture Address, 6/13/2009
    - Dartmouth Engineering Investiture Address - JJD, 6/13/2009
    - After the Fall: A Roadmap to Michigan's Future, 10/22/2009
    - Climate Change and American Know-How, 11/13/2009
    - Climate Change and American Know-How, 11/13/2009
    - Remarks to NSF Strategic Planning Group, 12/1/2009
    - Remarks to the NSF Strategic Planning Group, 12/1/2009
    - Beginnings, 2010
    - The Future of the University, 2010
    - Heartland Draft, 2010
    - Higher Education Today and Tomorrow: A Global Perspective, 2010
    - Hubs of Transformation: Leveraging the Great Lakes Research Complex for Energy Innovation, 2010
    - The Keys to Michigan's Future: Learning and Innovation, 2010
    - A Master Plan for Higher Education in the Midwest, 2010
    - Needed: A National Strategy to Preserve Public Research Universities, 2010
    - Paradigm Shifts, 2010
    - University Tribute to President Robben Fleming, 2010
    - Year, roles, activity, methods, and tools of JJD's academic life, 2010
    - Needed: a National Strategy to Preserve Public Research Universities, 1/3/2010
    - Needed: a National Strategy to Preserve Public Research Universities, 1/9/2010
    - ASU NAE Grand Challenges Conference, 4/9/2010
    - Hubs of Transformation: Leveraging the Great Lakes Research Complex for Energy Innovation, 2010-06
    - Conclusion - Challenges and Possible Strategies for Research Universities in Europe and the United States, 6/15/2010
    - Warning Redux, 6/15/2010
    - Global Sustainability Glion VIII, 2011
    - Midwest Master Plan, 2011
    - Midwest Master Plan Heartland Paper, 2011
    - The Third Century, 2011
    - The Future of the American Research University, 3/17/2011
    - Global Sustainability: Timescales, Magnitudes, Paradigms, and Black Swans, 6/18/2011
    - Engineering Design: A Foundation for a 21st Century Renaissance, 2011-07
    - Review of the University of Texas Report on Gas Shale Fracking, 11/26/2012
    - Are the Liberal Arts Still the Heart of the American Research University? Some Observations from An Engineering Professor..., 5/23/2013
    - The Impact of Technology on Discovery and Learning in Research Universities, 6/5/2013
    - Research Universities and the Future of America: A Study by the National Academies of the United States, 6/5/2013
    - Some (Belated) Observations on the Information Technology Strategic Plan, 7/1/2013
    - A Challenge to the Yale Class of 1964: Securing Educational Opportunities for Future Generations, 9/9/2013
    - A Half-Century of Technological Change, 9/9/2013
    - A Framing Paper for Research University Study, 9/20/2013
    - A 50 Year History of Social Diversity at UM, 2016
    - Adapting the University to the Constraints, Responsibilities and Opportunities of a New Age, 2016
    - Case Studies in Strategic Roadmapping in Higher Education, 2016
    - Charting the Course of the University of Michigan Over Half a Century, 2016
    - Creating the Future: The Promise of Public Research Universities for America, 2016
    - Energy Discovery-Innovation Institutes: A Step toward America's Energy Sustainability, 2016
    - Energy Discovery-Innovation Institutes: A Step toward America's Energy Sustainability (Summary), 2016
    - An Expedition to Glacier and Yellowstone, 2016
    - A Flexner Report for Engineering: The Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education, 2016
    - For the Love of Michigan, 2016
    - A Foundation for the 21st Century: A Progressive Framework for the National Science Foundation, 2016
    - The Future of the Public University in America: Beyond the Crossroads, 2016
    - The Inglis Highlands Estate: A Photographic History, 2016
    - National Science Foundation Awards Ceremony Program, 2016
    - Preparing the World's Research University's to Respond to an Era of Challenges and Change, 2016
    - The President's House: A Photographic History, 2016
    - Renewing and Updating the Vision for The Duderstadt Center (aka Media Union), 2016
    - Research Universities and the Future of America: Ten Breakthrough Actions Vital to Our Nation's Prosperity and Security, 2016
    - Research Universities and the Future of America: Ten Breakthrough Actions Vital to Our Nation's Prosperity and Security (Summary), 2016
    - The Third Century: A Roadmap the University of Michigan's Future, 2016
    - Tilting at Windmills: Policy Battles Won, Lost or Long Since Forgotten, 2016
    - Time to Get it Right: Staying Competitive in the New Economy, 2016
    - Universities of the World, 2016
    - University Priorities and Constraints, 2016
    - University Research for Innovation, 2016
    - The University of Michigan: A Photographic Saga, 2016
    - Adventures in Higher Education Policy, Millennium Project, 2017
    - The Duderstadt Center at 20 Years, Millennium Project, 2017
    - Case Studies in Strategic Roadmapping for University Planning, Millennium Project, 2017
    - A University for the 21st Century: Twenty Years Later, Millennium Project, 2017
    - An Operating Manual for the University of Michigan, 2018
    - Universities of the World, 2018
    - The University of Michigan Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences: A History, 2018